# **Zhou Yibo**

I am a Product / User Experience designer with a 10 year track record in diverse design disciplines, including Service Design, Product Strategy, and Communications Design. I believe that design can help businesses solve the problem of increasing lifetime value of customers.

#### CONTACT

(+65) 9140 7816 kateyibozhou@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/yibozhoukate/

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior UX & CRO (Conversion,

#### FEB 2023 - PRESENT

# Retention, Optimisation) Designer

## ExpressVPN, Singapore

Part of the web conversion optimisation team for ExpressVPN that helps drive conversion down sales funnels and grow the value of customers through high conversion web and app designs. Work collaboratively with Growth Marketers, Data Analysts, Engineers, Product Managers and Researchers.

- Triangulated quant and qual insights, data analytics, and past A/B experiments to provide design solutions grounded in behavioural psychology and UX heuristics.
- Designed for high impact web page (Order page). Design resulted in 8% uplift in average order value on Order page experiment.
- Increased user retention and renewal business revenue by 86% within 7 days of testing.
- Evangelised the adoption and integration of customer journey maps for ExpressVPN, as well as other KAPE brands (Cyber Ghost, Private Internet Access) to plug gaps in user experiences across the company.
- Initiated upskilling sessions for junior designers in cross-geo teams.

## User Experience Designer Foolproof, Singapore

OCT 2021 - FEB 2023

Worked principally as a Design lead, while also providing support in design projects, focusing on UX solutions for web and mobile platforms for various clients. Clients: DBS, Shell, Adobe.

- Analysed and transformed user insights from APAC markets to formulate product journey A/B testing, regional optimisation and adaptation for EMEA market.
- Directed localisation of a digital rewards and payment platform for launch across 4 markets within APAC.
- Worked on the Information Architecture for Treasury & Markets section for a leading bank in APAC.
- · Hosted sessions to allow upskilling within design team, centered around effective communication, conversion design, consulting framework amongst others.

#### **SKILLS**



#### Design

**UX** Design

Service Design

Art Direction

Illustration

#### Research

Qualitative research

#### Strategy

Co-create workshop facilitation

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Nanyang Polytechnic

Specialist Diploma in Service Design and Innovation

#### Nanyang Technological University

Bachelor of Fine Arts (Hons) Visual Communications

#### **LANGUAGES**

English

Mandarin

#### **DOMAIN INTERESTS**

Healthcare

Ecommerce

Sustainability

# **Zhou Yibo**

I am a Product / User Experience designer with a 10 year track record in diverse design disciplines, including Service Design, Product Strategy, and Communications Design. I believe that design can help businesses solve the problem of increasing lifetime value of customers.

#### CONTACT

(+65) 9140 7816 kateyibozhou@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/yibozhoukate/

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Communications Designer (Design Consulting for Markets)

MAY 2019 - SEP 2021

### Philips Electronics, Singapore

Part of the Philips Experience Design community. Responsible for providing primary consultative services / thought partnership for internal / external clientele.

- Supervised and mentored designers in formulating campaign strategy and managing asset delivery.
- Orchestrated design thinking workshops to architect solutions for C-Suite stakeholders.
- Led Male Grooming S1000 omnichannel campaign development for APAC through creative strategy and direction, generated 47% increase in sales within one month of launch.
- Pioneered E2E communications experience for Xiamen Cardiovascular Hospital (Greater China) with identification of demographic messaging and design, streamlining operational communication in the span of 6 months.

# Omni-Channel Designer

SEP 2016 - MAY 2019

### Sephora, Singapore

Supported omni-channel marketing campaigns across Retail and Digital platforms in APAC.

- Developed and localised campaigns that run through in-store visual communications and digital applications (Paid ads, Social, EDM, Mobile, Onsite).
- Helmed design and delivery of key annual campaigns (Sephora Private Sale, Black Friday, Great Singapore Sale, etc).
- Developed Sephora SEA guidelines for implementation across all markets.
- Drove experimentation and formulated strategic insights through analysis of design metrics (Impressions, CTR, conversion rates) to validate and coordinate campaign remodelling.

## Designer

SEP 2013 - SEP 2016

### NiCE Ltd, Singapore

Worked with principals and designers to create conceptual and strategic design solutions for FMCG brands in various consumer industries, with an emphasis on Beauty and Hair Care. Brands: Tiger Balm, Rejoice, Head & Shoulders, Pantene, Hugo Boss, Mengniu, Vidal Sassoon, Puma.

- Owned the Rejoice account for Greater China and APAC, involving packaging design, participating in brand vision workshops to develop its design direction across multiple product verticals.
- Lead designer for SK-II festive edition packaging 2016, for global launch.